Ralph J. Perk Jr. will be inducted by Congresswoman Mary Rose Okar. We all know
Pinehurst women, Okar. She was a 2012 inductee in the Cleveland Air National
Hall of Fame.
Along with her distinguished public service work, she's well known for her work,
Peace and Justice in Central America at the Middle East. She's a monitor for
the
Palestinian and Czechoslovakian elections. She attended Middle East peace
signings at the White House. She flew with President Clinton on Air Force One
to
Syria after a peace agreement was signed. She was also the national president
of
the American Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee, the ABC. So Congresswoman Okar
will induct Judge Rocky Ralph Perk.
And now as well, but I'm really inspired tonight, aren't you all? Isn't this
terrific?
With your reception doctor, I know everybody very well on this podium. And they're
fabulous people. And to let a Democrat introduce a Republican like Ralph Perk
shows what Cleveland's all about, that we need in Congress and the President.
You're good friends. Ralph Perk Jr. Do you know anybody who dislikes Ralph Perk
Jr.? He's the most
likable guy I know. He's got five brothers and one sister. His father was one
of the
absolute fabulous mayors of Cleveland. You know why I think that? Among other
reasons.
And I served in that era as a councilwoman because he cared about the
neighborhoods.
And that's, I think we have to go a little bit back to that area. Well, he
looks like his father,
Meripur, but don't forget he's part Italian and he's got that flair of his
mother,
Lucian. Ralph has been, and I'm not even going to details on the program, but
he's been in
Cleveland City Councilman. He's been elected mayor and president of the
Cleveland Board of
Education and elected and served 13 years as a Cleveland municipal judge. He's
won so many
awards if you want to know what they are. Three fro
years. You know, I have a devotion to, where's Father Kelly in here? Father
Kelly out of
our living room. Paris Ralph's Paris. Paris, right. But I have a devotion to St.
Louis
of the Little Following. One of the things she said that I think Ralph emulates
is all
you have to do is do simple things well. And that's what Ralph has done without
the fanfare
and trying to get the publicity and all that, that sometimes some people do.
But let his
mother, remember Lucy? I don't know if you remember Lucy. I mean, I know you
remember
her for the great one, but Lucy, who was very loyal, so loyal that she kept her
bowling league
commitment instead of going to the White House. I don't blame her. No,
seriously. That White
House would be kind of interesting. Fine. But Ralph was loyal also, was loyal
to his
parish. Who's my father? Loyal to his family. Loyal to his country. Two offices
where I
saw him in action. I served in Cleveland City Council with Ralph. In council,
he was not
controversial. He was the only Republican. I had city council. His father was
mayor. Never
did I ever see Ralph play that out. Like I gotta get this, I get that. It wasn't
like
that at all. In fact, probably he had worked harder to get things from his
father as mayor.
He was a councilman in a Slavic village. One of my favorite neighborhoods that
I was privileged
to represent in Congress and did not get a lot of perks, as I mentioned, from
his father
that I ever saw. You know, the Democratic members of city council had a caucus.
And we used to
meet at Pat Joyce's on 9th Street. I don't know if you remember where Pat Joyce's
was
right on the corner of there. And we have a, George Flores was the council
president
and a fabulous guy who, by the way, got along very well with Ralph. We were
convicted. Great
things together. But anyway, we had this caucus meeting and we had a little bit
of dinner.
And I said to George in my first term naivete cell for public life, I said to
George, "You
know, we're all here. There's only one person not here. Ralph Kirk. Why isn't
he invited?"
And George says, "Mayor Rose, he's a Republican. This is a Democratic caucus."
But the fact
is that Ralph was very, very well liked and very cooperative with his Congress.
My second
encounter as a public official, as a member of Congress now, was when Ralph,
did you know
that he was on the Cleveland Council Educational Board of Trustees for the city
of Cleveland?
Did anybody know that? He was president, elected president by his colleagues
when he could
vote for the board. Did I? I won't say that again. But anyway, Ralph was
president. In
Ira's and Congress, Ralph would come to Washington to lobby, not only me, he'd
go everywhere
to ask for help with the Cleveland students and the Cleveland public school
system. He
was fabulous. And we didn't know that. We didn't know that Ralph was doing that.
Probably
in many ways in his own, his fence. So he was carrying in conscientious. Here's
a Catholic
kid who went to Catholic schools fighting for the public school system. And I
think Ralph
was absolutely terrific and very, very concerned about the children in our
schools. And then
he became a Cleveland municipal judge for 13 years. And I don't know, Rob, can
you still
do that? You know, as a retiree to come back, substitute, right? I didn't ask
people about
Rob's reputation in preparation for this. Not that I didn't know, but they said
he was
the most balanced judge, which is what you need, and extraordinarily fair. He
knew how
the weight of the scales of justice was part of Ralph. And now he's still
active in lots
of ways. But his father, Mary Purr, founded something fabulous and probably a
prelude
in a way to what we are here tonight at the Cleveland International Hall of
Fame. His
father founded the American Nationalities Movement, which was very, very
inclusive.
And I love the way Mary Purr used to describe the people of Cleveland. He
called it a cultural
mosaic of people. And that's who we are. I think there's 112 different ethnic
groups
in Cleveland, Ohio. And so Ralph was nominated to be president, you know, third
removed for
the American Nationalities Movement by one of his father and Ralph's
girlfriends, who
is here tonight and was inducted on the memorial. And she should stand up
because she kept
that program going. I don't know. I don't know how to do that. I think I'll put
it up
there. Thank you. There she is. I think. Well, I asked, I hope you don't mind,
Ralph. Why
did you nominate Ralph Jr. to be president of the American Nationalities
Movement when
you retired from it after many years of service? And she said it wasn't because
he was the
son of the mayor who founded it. It was because he always volunteered. He
always took the
pictures. He always wrote, she told me you wrote the most beautiful letters to
people.
And I think that's a real talent as an old English teacher. So tonight, Judge
Kirk is
honored by being inducted to the Cleveland International Hall of Fame. Ralph
Kirk Jr.
is truly deserving, a very fine person. And you know what? He's a great guy.
And I'm
proud to know you, Ralph, and proud to be your friend, and proud to be, as we
always
have been, when we work together, when we work with you, Jan, non-partisan. God
bless
you.
[applause]